Hello, and welcome to Lesson 25 of this introduction to calculus with Wolfram U.
大家好 欢迎来到本次与沃尔夫兰大学合作的微积分入门第 25 课
The topic for this lesson is the fundamental theorem of calculus.
本节课的课题是微积分的基本定理
Let’s begin with a brief overview of the lesson.
我们先来简单介绍一下本课的内容
So far in this course, we have talked about differential calculus
到目前为止这门课程中我们已经学了微分学
and a bit of integral calculus.
和一点积分学知识
Now originally, differential calculus arose in the problem of
现在 微分是在以下问题中产生的
finding the tangent line to a curve like you see over here—
找出曲线的切线 就像你在这里看到的一样
a sine curve, and you want a tangent line at a point—
一个正弦曲线 而你想在一个点上有一条切线
and that’s what differential calculus tries to do.
而这正是微分学试图做的事情
It tries to find the slope of that line at a point.
它试图找到该线在某一点的斜率
Now integral calculus, on the other hand, solves the problem
现在积分微积分则解决了以下问题
of finding the area under the curve for a function.
求函数的曲线下面积
If you look at a sine function, then it tries to find
如果你看一个正弦函数 那么它就会尝试找到
the area under this curve between the two limits over here.
这条曲线下在这里的两个极限之间的面积
Now what the fundamental theorem of calculus does is
现在微积分的基本定理的作用就是
it ties these two ideas together.
它把这微分和积分联系在一起
In this lesson, what we’ll do is to go over
在这一课中 我们要做的是去了解一下这些内容
this very important theorem.
这个是非常重要的定理
In fact, by far, this is the most basic fact of calculus
事实上到目前为止 这是微积分最基本的知识
that you really should know in order to apply it in practice.
你真的应该知道它以便在实践中应用
Okay. Let’s begin with the idea of an integral function.
好吧 我们先从积分函数的概念开始
Here I’m defining a function of x
在这里 我定义了一个 x 的函数。
which is given by the integral of t from 0 to x.
由 t 从 0 到 x 的积分给出
Basically what it does it is takes the function g[t] = t
基本上 它的作用是将函数 g[t]=t
and integrates from 0 to x.
从 0 到 x 求积分
Obviously if x is 0, then the value is 0
显然 如果 x 为 0 那么数值为 0
because you’re integrating from 0 to 0, so you get back 0.
因为你是从 0 到 0 的积分 所以你得到的是 0
In general, it calculates the area under the curve from 0 to x.
一般来说 它计算的是 0 到 x 的曲线下面积
That’s the integral function f[x],
这就是积分函数 f[x]
and here is a graph of the function and x.
这里是函数和 x 的图像
What we notice is that as x increases,
我们注意到的是 随着 x 的增加
the value of this function also increases
这个函数的值也会增加
because the upper limit over here increases.
因为这边的上限增加
The integral function is increasing because the area increases,
积分函数在增大因为随着 x 的增加
in this case, as x increases.
面积也增大
Now the point is that there is actually an explicit formula
现在的问题是 对于这个积分函数
for this integral function.
其实有一个明确的公式
What we do is we begin with the integral from 0 to x
我们要从 0 到 x 的积分开始
and break it up into n parts, and then we set up the Riemann sum.
将其分解为 n 部分 然后我们设置黎曼和
In this case, the Riemann sum is going to be g(xi)—
在这种情况下 黎曼和将是 g(xi)
those are sample points—times the width of each subinterval.
这些都是样本点乘以每个子间隔的宽度
Then you sum them all up and take a limit,
然后你把它们汇总起来 取一个极限
and what you get back is x^2/2.
而你得到的是 x^2/2
But then you remind yourself that the antiderivative of g[t]
但你又提醒自己 g[t] 的反导数
is also t^2/2 plus some constant.
也是 t^2/2 加上一些常数
Here’s a check for that.
这里有一个检查
It looks like the integral function for g[t]
看起来像是 g[t] 的积分函数
is actually an antiderivative of g[t].
实际上是 g[t] 的反导数
Now that looks very surprising,
现在看起来非常令人惊讶
so what we’ll do is we’ll try and go a bit deeper
所以我们要做的是 我们将尝试并去更深一点
and develop some intuition for why that might be the case.
并对为什么会出现这种情况产生一些直觉
Let’s begin over here with the integral function again
我们再从积分函数开始吧
and think of the difference at two points, f[x + h] and f[x]—
并思考两个点的区别 f[x+h] 和 f[x]
two close-by points with h being very small.
两个相近的点 h 很小
Now that difference over here would just be
现在 这里的差异将只是
the area of a tiny strip because h is very small.
因为 h 非常小 所以是一个小带子的面积
Here’s a picture.
这里有一张图
The area of that strip is simply the width times the height,
该条带的面积只是宽度乘以高度
which is just the g[x], so the area is h * g[x].
这只是 g[x] 所以面积是 h*g[x]
But then that is f[x + h] – f[x], so if you divide,
但那就是 f[x+h]-f[x] 所以如果你做除法
then you get back this relation over here.
然后你回顾这个关系
As h goes to 0, that says that f'[x] = g[x].
由于 h 为 0 所以说 f'[x]=g[x]
In other words, f[x] is an antiderivative of g[x].
换句话说 f[x] 是 g[x] 反导数
It is this remarkable fact which is summarized
正是这个事实被概括在
in the fundamental theorem of calculus.
微积分基本定理中
There are two versions.
它有两个版本
That’s version 1 over here.
这是版本一
It says that if you have a continuous function g
它说 如果你有一个连续函数 g
and you define f to be an integral from 0 to x—
你定义 f 为从 0 到 x- 的积分
from a to x, in this case—then what you get back
从 a 到 x 在这种情况下 你得到的是
is a function, an integral function, and this integral function
是一个积分函数 而这个积分函数
is actually an antiderivative of g.
实际上是 g 的反导数
In other words, f'[x] is equal to g[x].
换句话说 f'[x] 等于 g[x]
Let’s try and understand that a bit more
让我们试着去理解一下吧
by looking at some examples.
通过看一些例子
Let’s say you have the function f[x] given by the integral
假设你有函数 f[x] 其积分为
from 0 to x for Sin(√1 + t^2)dt and you integrate it.
从 0 到 x 为 Sin(√1+t^2)dt
Then you just get back Sin(√1 + x^2).
那么你只需取回 Sin(√1+x^2)
Here’s a check; namely, if we take
这里有一个检查 即如果我们用
the derivative of the integral function,
积分函数的导数
you will get back just the original function.
你将得到的只是原来的函数
That’s the summary over here which says that
这就是这边的总结
if you take a function, integrate it and then differentiate it,
如果你把一个函数积分后在求导
you get back the original function.
你会找回原来的函数
Now the problem is the upper limit itself
现在的问题是上限本身
might depend on x in some complicated way.
可能以某种复杂的方式依赖于 x
In that case, you must apply the chain rule.
在这种情况下 你必须应用链式法则
Let’s say g[x] is the integral 0 to x^2
假设在相同函数中
of the same function.
g[x] 是 0 到 x^2 的积分
Then if you differentiate that with respect to x,
那么如果你对 x 进行微分
you will need to account for the x^2,
你需要考虑到 x^2
so you get back a factor of 2x over here.
所以你在这里得到的是 2x 的系数
Let’s check that.
让我们检查一下
You get back 2xSin(√1 + x^4).
你得到的是 2xSin(√1+x^4)
Okay. Let’s now go on to talking about why these integral functions
好了 现在我们继续说说为什么
are useful at all.
这些积分函数都是有用的
There is a function called the Fresnel function
有一个函数叫菲涅尔函数
which really quite useful in optics and highway design.
这在光学和公路设计中真的相当有用
After all, if you design a highway or you design, let’s say,
毕竟 如果你设计一条高速公路或者
a very long line, you need to worry about the turns,
一条很长的线 你需要关注一下拐点
and that’s where this Fresnel function comes in.
这就是这个菲涅尔函数的作用
It’s the integral function of a sine function.
它是正弦函数的积分函数
We have this in the Wolfram Language.
我们在 Wolfram 语言中就有这个函数
It’s called FresnelS.
这就是所谓的 FresnelS 函数
That’s FresnelS and its derivative on the same plot.
那是 FresnelS 和它在同一图像上的导数
The blue plot is the Fresnel function and the orange plot is
蓝色图是菲涅尔函数 橙色图是它的导数
its derivative, which is just the sine function over here.
也就是这边的正弦函数而已
Another very useful function is the error function,
另一个非常有用的功能是误差函数
which is also an integral function,
这也是一个积分函数
and that’s used in statistics and probability.
运用在统计学和概率学
Here is the error function with its derivative.
下面是误差函数及其导数
You have the error function, which is blue,
你有蓝色的误差函数
over here, and the derivative.
在这里 和导数
It’s just a normal probability curve.
这只是一条正常的概率曲线
What happens is as you approach very large values,
当你接近非常大的数值时 会发生什么
the probability of everything being covered is almost 1,
覆盖一切的概率几乎为 1
so that’s why the values over here are almost 1.
所以这就是为什么这边的数值几乎是 1
Okay. Now there is another more useful version
好了现在还有一个更有用的基本定理版本
of the fundamental theorem, and that’s version 2,
就是第二版
which says that suppose you have a function f
假设你有函数 f
and you find an antiderivative of that function by some means.
而你通过某种方式找到该函数的反导数
Then the value of the integral from a to b of this function f
那么这个函数从 a 到 b 的积分值 f
is the antidervative at b minus the antiderivative at a.
是 b 的反导数减去a的反导数
In other words, the integral of an antiderivative
换句话说，一个反导数的积分
can be found quite easily by simply working out
可以很容易地找到，只要计算出
the difference between the values at the upper and the lower limits.
上下限值之差
That says that differentiation and integration
这说明 差异化和一体化
are actually the inverse processes of each other.
其实都是彼此的逆过程
That’s quite a remarkable fact.
这是一个相当了不起的事实
For example, if you’re asked to find
例如 如果你被要求计算出
the integral of x^2 from 1 to 4,
x^2 从 1 到 4 的积分
then you first work out the antiderivative, which is x^3/3.
那么你首先要计算出反演数 即 x^3/3
Then you plug in the upper and lower limits,
然后你插上上下限
so you get 4^3/3 – 1^3/3, and the answer 21.
所以你得到 4^3/3-1^3/3 答案为 21
You can check that with Integrate and get back just the same result.
你可以用 Integrate 函数检查一下 得到的结果也一样
That brings me to the end of this lesson,
本课到这里结束了
but the main point is that the fundamental theorem of calculus
但主要的是 微积分的基础定理
is one of the most important theorems in calculus
是微积分中最重要的定理之一
because it says that differentiation and integration
因为它说 差异化和一体化
are the inverse processes of each other.
是彼此的逆过程
In fact, its real utility is to compute integrals
事实上 它的真正用途是计算积分
by using antiderivatives
用反导数
Basically, using the antiderivatives is much easier
基本上，使用反导数比使用黎曼和
than using Riemann sums.
要容易得多
Instead of calculating Riemann sums,
不用计算黎曼和
you would calculate antiderivatives.
直接计算反导数
The next lesson will talk about indefinite integrals.
下节课将讲到不定积分
But before that, do review this lesson over here
但在这之前 请先在这边复习一下这堂课吧
because we have covered one of the most important theorems in calculus,
因为我们已经涵盖了微积分中最重要的定理之一
and that’s going to be used all the time.
而这将会被一直使用。
Let’s stop over here.
今天就到这里
Thank you very much,
非常感谢您
and I hope you have learned a lot in this lesson.
并希望你在这一课中学到很多东西
翻译 彭彦鸿